## **Eduardo Ribas**

Web Developer • Technical in Internet Informatics São Paulo, Brazil • ribasdois@gmail.com

## About me

I am a web developer with over 2 years of professional experience in the field, always aiming to provide accessible and functional experiences for all types of users.

Additionally, I strive to bring designs to life with the highest level of fidelity.

My main skills involve developing applications with a focus not only on the user experience but also on the developer's experience. Creating scalable code and providing users with exceptional navigation are fundamental pillars of good service.

## **Strengths**

User experience and interface, high-fidelity design replication (pixel-perfect), and scalable, easily maintainable code.

## **Skills**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React JS, Next JS, C#, MUI, Tailwind CSS, Shadon UI, Figma, Git, Prisma ORM, PlanetScale, MySQL, SQL Server, Stripe, Resend

## Experience

## Tecnologia Única · Pre-Junior Full Stack Developer 2 · 2023 to present

As a full-time developer, I continue to actively work on all tasks related to the startup's platform where I work. I develop modular and well-documented components that are easy to implement across various use cases, while always aiming for optimal performance and ensuring they are always accessible. I participate in refactoring various functionalities to improve code readability and facilitate future maintenance. I have experience with file uploads to our .NET-based API, payment flows integrating tools like MercadoPago and PagarMe, authentication using JWT (JSON Web Tokens), and various integrations with external APIs. I communicate my ideas with utmost clarity to ensure all my teammates understand my thought process. Whenever I encounter a problem, I analyze it thoroughly, thus plotting the best way to solve it while consuming the least resources possible. I continue to deepen my knowledge in React, SQL Server, and C#.

# Devely • Final Course Project • 2023 to present

was an incredible opportunity for me to develop some of my soft skills, such as leadership, proactivity, and persistence. I delved deeply into technologies like NextJS, TypeScript, Shadon UI, Prisma ORM, PlanetScale, Stripe, Cloudinary, MySQL, Resend, and Figma, gaining experience in creating a complete platform, from sketch to development. I dealt with user authentication, email sending, payment flows, and image uploads to a cloud storage service. It was a comprehensive experience that gave me much more confidence in the quality of my work.

My final project for the High School Diploma integrated with a Technical Degree in Internet Informatics

# My internship at Tecnologia Única allowed me to learn more about startups and develop my technical

Tecnologia Unica • Intern • 2022 to 2023

and social skills. Communication was essential for adapting to an environment that was new to me at the time. At the startup where I worked, I developed several landing pages and actively participated in the development and maintenance of our platform. I used technologies like NextJS, ReactJS, TypeScript, SASS, MUI, C#, and SQL Server.

# Durante o meu tempo como padrinho voluntário do projeto Pequenos Talentos, um projeto que visa

Pequenos Talentos · Volunteer · 2022 to 2023

capacitar jovens do ensino fundamental na área de tecnologia e auxiliá-los na ingressão do mercado de trabalho, eu pude auxiliar os alunos no desenvolvimento de suas tarefas, bem como atuar no desenvolvimento e manutenção da landing page do projeto utilizando tecnologias como React, SASS e Tailwind CSS.

# FETEPS · Volunteer · 2023 até 2024

Souza and other participating institutions, featuring innovative characteristics, social transformation, technology application, and creativity. I worked in a team with various people with different levels of knowledge in prototyping and developing a platform to manage various data related to the event. We used Fluent UI as the design base for this platform to provide a familiar experience for the administrators who would be using the system, as they were already familiar with the Microsoft ecosystem due to a partnership.

FETEPS is a space for demonstrating and socializing projects developed by students from Centro Paula

**Education** 

ETEC Maria Cristina Medeiros • 2021 - 2023 • High School

High School Diploma with a Technical Degree in Internet Informatics.